<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-12-20T23:26:44+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Daveed Silva</title><subtitle>Daveed is a psychomagician and web developer based in NY. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">On being</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/on-being/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On being"/><published>2023-11-04T04:20:15+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-04T04:20:15+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/on-being</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/on-being/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="we-do-this-not-because-is-easy-but-because-we-thought-it-would-be-easy">We do this not because is easy, but because we thought it would be easy</h2> <p>When I share with someone that I’m undocumented or illegal, I love when their response is “Hell yeah!”. Is important to embrace reality with pride, humor, and berraquera. I’m lucky to have partners, customers, friends, and collaborators that make it seem like I’m just like any one of them.</p> <p>I’m not a unique case. Many refugees and undocumented people landed comfortably on a plane, student or work visa, and, for one reason or another, entered a state of limbo—overstaying, missing deadlines, and navigating confusing bureaucratic steps. I chose to come in an challenging way, it has shown me parts of society easily ignored.</p> <p>La vida no es solo blanco y negro; is messy and radically contradictory, absurd. I grew up in a city dedicated to nature, art, music, and community, shadowed by narcos, sicarios y corrupción. The same person and place in my memories can be a contradictory source of joy and pain. My parents always emphasized the importance of threating everyone with respect, and building community - and here in the US I’ve found a home in the resilience of others, joining in a variety of places from undocumented high school students to puerto rico after a hurricane.</p> <p>Mis compitas, gonorreitas, the ones who’ll drop everything to show up, who’ll share the little they have, are usually other immigrants, sharing our recipes and stories from lovely places abroad. Our challenges can’t shrink our dreams. <em>pa’atras ni pa coger impulso</em>.</p> <p>There’s another election in the US tomorrow, we survived 3 national presidential campaigns being called criminals and garbage.</p> <p>Whoever ends up winning doesn’t change the reality for millions of us. It won’t automatically make it easier for my friends in Colombian having their appointments postponed by months. Real change will come by participating in our local communities, and joining forces to find solutions to systemic problems.</p> <p>Our cells evolve through biological exchange, and our societies evolve through cultural and intellectual exchange. Así es como crecemos, como artistas, ingenieros, filósofos. The French helped us break from Spain and brought us <em>le droit politique</em>, American movies fuel our cineastas, and Nueva York nos dio un lienzo donde dibujamos la salsa.</p> <p>Be one of those people who leans into abundance, opens your life to others. Call things by their name, not to settle but to inspire action. Find ways to improve something for your family and friends. Political parties won’t even matter. We’re creating something better, algo que vale la pena.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/posts/iran.png" alt="Iran"/></p> <p><img src="/assets/img/posts/we-do-this-not-because-is-easy-1.png" alt="We do it not because is easy, but because we thought it would be easy"/></p> <blockquote> <p>I wish it need not have happened in my time,” said Frodo. “So do I,” said Gandalf, “and so do all who live to see such times. But that is not for them to decide. All we have to decide is what to do with the time that is given us.</p> </blockquote> <p>— Gandalf</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wish it need not have happened in my time," said Frodo. "So do I," said Gandalf, "and so do all who live to see such times. But that is not for them to decide. All we have to decide is what to do with the time that is given us.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Santo Cabrón at Black Rock City 2023</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/santo-cabron-brc-23/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Santo Cabrón at Black Rock City 2023"/><published>2023-09-10T04:20:15+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-10T04:20:15+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/santo-cabron-brc-23</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/santo-cabron-brc-23/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="intro">Intro</h2> <p>As one of the few handsome first time camp leaders of Black Rock City this year I feel obligated to describe my experience in a format that others can mock or be inspired by. I have been a part of Black Rock City for several years in multiple teams, been a part of multiple teams at regionals and renegades as well.</p> <h2 id="history">History</h2> <p>In 2022 I did open camping with one of my best friends, Kyle, and during the dust storms and harsher days we hosted people in our small structures and had enough extra beers that we were able to share and a fire where wanderers can sit around. That year we stayed in 3:30 I, because I was 33 years old and the newspaper had a 33 on the front page.</p> <p>A few weeks after the burn I had a vision that showed me the Santo Cabron idea and potential and started recruiting folks to join our potential camp, hosted a couple of parties in Manhattan and got some followers to believe in our mission.</p> <h2 id="pre-event-planning">Pre-event planning</h2> <p>We tried following the available resources out there as much as possible, signed up for BLAST, participated in the camp symposium, RIDE, HUBS, etc. Created a master spreadsheet, a google form for applications and started gathering interest from folks, our plan was to cap it at 20 people and we applied for 100 X 100 Feet lot in the 3 sector.</p> <p>Our leadership philosophy was to create working groups, have a single point of truth (the spreadsheet) and go over check lists and recalling old experiences to ensure the least amount of work, require fewer meetings, encourage self-reliance and participation.</p> <p>We spoke to a few neighboring camps, and thru the HUBS program we were also able to coordinate some logistics to pretend to save the environment, reduce costs and ease the logistics. Black Rock City community college was particularly helpful, and connected us with Jeff Temen from Gerlach to get our water. Our placers were awesome, and we encouraged our burgins to attend local events, watch videos and prepare themselves.</p> <p>Getting the right people on board from the start and empowering them was super important, our core leads are builders, artists and experienced burners that were able to solve very complex issues easily by the nature of having done it before. Special shot out to camp NICHY and John, only a small set of their campers was attending this year and we connected to share our space and their infrastructure for the common good.</p> <h2 id="build-week">Build week</h2> <p>The rain delayed our entrance a couple of days into Burning Man, so we used that time in Reno to prepare extra, pack things, buy things, and have those last final details ready for all the campers.</p> <p>Building went pretty uneventful, shade, kitchen, etc, the usual.</p> <h2 id="burn-week">Burn week</h2> <p>Burn week went pretty uneventful. We were located in the 3 sector, supported by the best placers and most awesome peeps in the city.</p> <h2 id="rain-week">Rain week</h2> <p>We modified our structures to make them waterproof, hosted some parties under the dome, shared some of our additional resources with other camps.</p> <h2 id="exodus">Exodus</h2> <p>We waited about 4 hours in line with the truck, left the afternoon after the Man Burn. Packed the stuff in the storage, washed the truck at a cool spot in Reno ourselves and returned it.</p> <h2 id="reflections">Reflections</h2> <p>The principles work, the guides work, the community works. There are many existing resources out there already to look at, and beautiful communities of camp leaders, chefs, builders and teams ready to support you.</p> <p>Before the rain our campers were having a regular party time in the desert, afterwards it became a real family.</p> <h2 id="encouragement">Encouragement</h2> <p>Create smaller camps, sillier camps, less work and more creativity, camps with 200 people and sound systems that run 4 hours a day are nice and all but the heart of our city are the weird bars and people staying up late in their frontage by the fire.</p> <h2 id="appendix">Appendix</h2> <h3 id="finances">Finances</h3> <p>Will share a breakdown of the money collected and spent. We definitely went over budget, thankfully some campers apported extra to compensate.</p> <h3 id="spreadsheet">Spreadsheet</h3> <p>Will anonymize or turn into a template and post here</p> <h3 id="logistics-providers">Logistics providers:</h3> <p>Here’s some of the places and services we used.</p> <ul> <li>we got our truck from U-haul, call in person and try finding the right friendly person who knows you’re going to burning man and won’t charge you a huge fee, we shared it Mo’Better Burners, a camp run by a good friend</li> <li>we washed the 26 foot truck by hand for around $50 at one of those coin operated places with power washers, air dryers and vacuums</li> <li>we got water delivered on site by OSS provider Jeff Temen in Gerlach</li> <li>we had a big water tank for grey water, and we’d flag a porto truck and pay them cash for grey water removal</li> <li>bought groceries, food and snacks and de-moop them ahead of time in Reno</li> <li>international campers rented bikes in reno, some were picked up by camp or other campers in the way there</li> <li>nyc burners used the nyc container camp to get their things delivered on playa</li> </ul> <p><img src="/assets/img/posts/santo-cabron-kitchen.JPG" style="max-width: 100%; margin-bottom: 16px;" alt="logo no oficial de la asociacion caleña para la promocion y la defensa de la cultura que promueve la callejera saludable, segura y con condom, con abreviatura: ACPDCPCSSC o a ce pe de ce pe ce ese ese ce para mas corto. la imagen depicta a un conejo salvaje en un valle en llamas."/></p> <h2 id="get-involved">Get involved</h2> <p>If you’re read this you’re likely already involved, stand in front of a mirror and sing the theme song to summon a santo cabrón.</p> <h2 id="stickers">Stickers</h2> <p>The sticker this year was a regular word sticker with the word “perica” on it. Perica is a word in my country for a female parrot, our national bird.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tales of a mythical creature visiting BRC]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Callejera, el arte marcial colombiano y su historia.</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/nyerismo-callejerismo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Callejera, el arte marcial colombiano y su historia."/><published>2023-06-06T12:12:42+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-06T12:12:42+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/nyerismo-callejerismo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/nyerismo-callejerismo/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>También conocida como ñerismo.</strong></p> <p>Callejera was born in the streets of Colombia simultaneously through the centuries of encounters with cabrones, those who survived would describe discovering new ancient secrets and dedicating their life to la escuela de la calle.</p> <p>There’s an ancient and ongoing oral tradition, which also comes with many disagreements, however the most accepted belt ranges are described as follow:</p> <p>white: gomelito</p> <p>white blue: cuatro ojos</p> <p>blue: nyero</p> <p>blue red: lacrilla</p> <p>red: hamponcito</p> <p>green: gonorreilla</p> <p>green second dan: gonoreilla doble hp</p> <p>Todo seguidor del santo cabron se alimenta bien y practica callejera y otras cumbias con frecuencia</p> <p>Our logo depicts a bunny because it is from the wilderness and the constant awe at creation that we can learn the most about ourselves</p> <h2 id="acpdcpcssc">ACPDCPCSSC</h2> <p>La asociacion caleña para la promocion y la defensa de la cultura que promueve la callejera saludable, segura y con condom, con abreviatura: ACPDCPCSSC o a ce pe de ce pe ce ese ese ce para más corto.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/posts/callejera.png" style="max-width: 100%; margin-bottom: 16px;" alt="logo no oficial de la asociacion caleña para la promocion y la defensa de la cultura que promueve la callejera saludable, segura y con condom, con abreviatura: ACPDCPCSSC o a ce pe de ce pe ce ese ese ce para mas corto. la imagen depicta a un conejo salvaje en un valle en llamas."/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to Colombian martial arts and rankings]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Burning Stones at Disorient Country Club</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/burning-stones/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Burning Stones at Disorient Country Club"/><published>2023-06-02T12:42:42+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-02T12:42:42+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/burning-stones</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/burning-stones/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="burning-stones-at-disorient-country-club">Burning Stones at disorient country club</h1> <p><img src="/assets/img/posts/disorient.png" style="max-width: 100%; margin-bottom: 16px;" alt="disorient country club entrance"/></p> <p>Growing up I loved my country club, our family would go to the Club San Fernando in Cali, Colombia, and we had friends who were members of others and it was a common weekend tradition to hang out by the pool and get in trouble.</p> <p>Last year I met the amazing team at Disorient, and their country club, and was happy to be accepted in their family. For this year’s Country Club I took over their bar with a new redesign and offerings that our members loved.</p> <p>This is our little secret, when you find yourself in the catskills, look for the country club and the secret burning stones bar in the forest.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/posts/burningstones.png" style="max-width: 100%;" alt="disorient country club entrance"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Excited to announce the opening of our dive bar at the disorient country club]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Encuentra tu voz leadership workshop</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/encuentra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Encuentra tu voz leadership workshop"/><published>2023-04-20T12:42:42+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-20T12:42:42+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/encuentra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/encuentra/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="encuentra-tu-voz-leadership-workshop">Encuentra tu voz leadership workshop</h1> <p>When looking for professional advice, it is often hard to find masters that can teach other coaches cultural competency. In order to learn how to teach this skill, it is very important that you can connect to your most vulnerable self in a safe way to find the inner voice behind all the masks and learn how to integrate that information into your practice so you can guide others in a similar way.</p> <p>This coaching methodology includes practices of logotherapy and bilingual storytelling by professional artists that can help you find your unique mission in life and express it through poetry to craft a cohesive leadership style and the confidence to inspire others.</p> <h2 id="why">Why</h2> <p>Vulnerability is often praised but rarely attained.</p> <h2 id="how">How</h2> <p>We will go through 4 steps, the length and complexity will vary by your request and potential deadlines.</p> <p><strong>1 - Exploring your fears -</strong> your potential hides in your fears, your mission hides in the places you avoid, let’s explore them to create a set of psychomagical experiences that will let you overcome them.</p> <p><strong>2 - Integrate your new mission statement -</strong> after your discovery is over we can design daily activities that integrate in your schedule to help you integrate them firmly.</p> <p><strong>3 - Write down your narrative -</strong> we will do a few creative writing assignments and rounds of editing until you have a satisfactory story you can firmly believe in, and you feel proud presenting</p> <p><strong>4 - Translate to a different language, culture or industry -</strong> this step is the most important when trying to connect with a new culture whether familiar or unknown, guided by culturally competent coaches, we will rewrite and the story in a way that is pleasant to the community, you can firmly believe in, and proudly present it.</p> <h2 id="documenting">Documenting</h2> <p>We recommend journaling through the process, and in general, include some form of journaling in your daily schedule. Adding the exercise prompts to your journal will allow you to practice this technique multiple times in the future. We recommend additionally writing the reason behind the prompts, it will allow you to better write your own in your coaching practice.</p> <p>Look at yourself in the mirror and say beetlejuice’s name 3 times before requesting a quote.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This coaching methodology includes practices of logotherapy and bilingual storytelling by professional artists that can help you find your unique mission in life and express it through poetry to craft a cohesive leadership style and the confidence to inspire others]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cabronera</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/cabronera/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cabronera"/><published>2023-04-03T12:42:42+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-03T12:42:42+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/cabronera</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/cabronera/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="cabronera">Cabronera</h1> <p>Desigining a stage structure that packs well and can be transported, build and break down easily for multiple burning man events around the country.</p> <p>The design builds on years of experience of structures in the desert, and other high risk regions. It uses lightweight material, easy to acquire and replace, easy to prepackage and install.</p> <p><strong>Introduction</strong></p> <p>Cabroneras are an ancient form of sacred comunal structure from the andean indigenous peoples. Also known by other names like Maloka, choza’eguadua, mariconada, playa labs shade structure, kfar hanokdim.</p> <p>Crossing the portal we summon will remind you of those long story nights in the desert near Jerusalem, where the bedouins share their stash with lucky wanderers</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cabronera]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The secrets of Kabbalah</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/secret-of-kabalah/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The secrets of Kabbalah"/><published>2023-01-17T12:42:42+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-17T12:42:42+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/secret-of-kabalah</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/secret-of-kabalah/"><![CDATA[<p>Pirke Abot asks whose wise? and the answer is the key to understanding the secrets of the universe. Follow the clues and be more intentional.</p> <p><img src="posts/santocabron3x3.png" alt="santo cabron"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[the key to unlocking permanent flow state and unlocking your intuition]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A framework for sustainable communities</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/cdd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A framework for sustainable communities"/><published>2023-01-17T12:42:42+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-17T12:42:42+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/cdd</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/cdd/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="community-driven-development">Community driven development</h1> <p><strong>Introduction</strong></p> <p>I want to propose a framework for technical product development and feature design that pays close attention to the needs of the community, can adapt to changes and is proving useful, understanding that our features transcend the websites our users visit.</p> <p>The framework is designed with input from experts in their different fields who have come together to design the ideal roadmap for a startup, one that is able to engage their community and its internal collaborators and access their higher potential, and endorsed by others.</p> <p><strong>Justification</strong></p> <p>A <strong>community startup</strong> has elements of its community in all departments, it must embody trust and support for its employees and members, the force of the startup then comes from the community much more so than anything the startup can build itself.</p> <p>The community for the startup can exists before any code is written, like Product Hunt that launched as a newsletter, and it lives beyond the technical features like Reddit AFK meetups.</p> <p><strong>The goal of our startups is to connect some kind of people to another and in some instances charge a fee for facilitating that connection</strong>. The day that we do that really well investors and paid users will come after us. <strong>Follow excellence and success will chase you —</strong> Ranchoddas Shamaldas Chanchad.</p> <p>User interviews reveal that users are eager to collaborate and feel supported by the thought of the community. The investors are looking for good deals and overlooked opportunities. <strong>Investors, founders and operators know that communities are powerful</strong>.</p> <p>Launching the community earlier and allowing members to communicate, and having channels of communication with them can help us reach our internal goals faster, bring awareness to what we’re doing, support other founders in our community, organically lead to new startups and teams being born, lead us to great talent, and create an audience for our paid interactions.</p> <p>A community driven development approach involves very good communication across departments, it needs clear guidelines and culture, and it comes with challenges. It requires highly qualified and motivated individuals and it rewards them with unique challenges.</p> <p>The goal is to instill a sense that the community already exists and the members are metaphorically building this together with us. The development team must understand and adapt to user feedback without disturbing internal processes, while supporting the business and operational aspects of the company.</p> <p>Potential members of the community and investors feel more involved and ready to collaborate in the difficult journey. Others might quietly follow along, waiting for a particular update to increase their involvement, while still feeling part of the community.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/posts/cdd.png" style="max-width: 100%;" alt="did you know that I'm not a famous stock photo model?"/></p> <blockquote> <p>did you know that I’m not a famous <a href="https://jopwellcollection.jopwell.com/jopwell_latinxcollection/p/MjkwODc5MTY5Ng==-MzM1NDQxNTc3Ng/">stock photo model</a>?</p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Create startups as a community]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">decomodify wellbeing</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/decomodify-wellbeing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="decomodify wellbeing"/><published>2023-01-10T07:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-10T07:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/decomodify-wellbeing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2023/decomodify-wellbeing/"><![CDATA[<p>While is very encouraging to see more people talking about their wellbeing, particularly mental health, it still bothers me significantly how there’s so many people trying to take advantage of it for profit. This is not a new concern; when Deepak Chopra visited Colombia in 2006, we had the chance to be on the organizing team and see behind the scenes of the wellness industry and its disregard for wellbeing.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/posts/chopra.jpg" alt="my younger brother and deepak chopra" style="max-width: 100%"/></p> <p>Today we see several startups taking advantage of this, <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-us/health/medical/scary-easy-sketchy-as-hell-how-startups-are-pushing-adderall-on-tiktok/ar-AA11dWDm">pushing pills</a> on people, selling overpriced subscriptions, trying to gate keep substances and force price increases, while at the same time forcing people into alienation, loneliness, debt and constant cycles of suffering that trap individuals in a vicious circle that is difficult to escape. Somehow we know that <a href="https://www.consulting.ca/news/2551/mckinsey-faces-class-action-lawsuit-for-alleged-role-in-opioid-crisis-in-canada">consultants are creating marketing pitches to kill thousands of people with opioids</a> and yet, people keep trusting them and the other initiatives they promote. None of them go to prison or face any consequence, all the power of the state must be used to invent a war on drugs to uphold white supremacy and the <a href="https://www.gatewayfoundation.org/addiction-blog/racism-war-on-drugs/">racists values</a> that allow capitalism to exist. The iran-contra scandal is well known, and I hope more information is also revealed on the ways the Colombian narco government and the USA worked together to control the cocaine market.</p> <h2 id="decomodification">Decomodification</h2> <h2 id="the-power-of-habit">The power of habit</h2> <h2 id="community">Community</h2> <h2 id="psychedelics">Psychedelics</h2> <h2 id="practical-reads">Practical reads</h2> <p><a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/radical-healership-how-to-build-a-values-driven-healing-practice-in-a-profit-driven-world-laura-mae-northrup/17051557">Radical healership</a></p> <p><a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/the-will-to-meaning-foundations-and-applications-of-logotherapy-viktor-e-frankl/11653436?ean=9780142181263">The will to meaning - applications of logotherapy</a></p> <p><a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/logotherapy-for-teens-with-expressive-arts-techniques-group-therapy-book-julie-l-quigley-ncc-lmhc/18523988?ean=9781669827078">Applied Logotherapy for kids with art</a></p> <p><a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/the-pain-we-carry-healing-from-complex-ptsd-for-people-of-color-natalie-y-gutierrez/18058034?ean=9781684039319">Healing from CPTSD for people of color</a></p> <h2 id="the-silva-method">the silva method</h2> <p>While looking for pictures of me and Deepak Chopra I found out there’s already a <a href="https://silvamethod.com/about">Silva method</a>, based on a <a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/you-the-healer-the-world-famous-silva-method-on-how-to-heal-yourself-and-others-silva-stone/9469266?ean=9780915811373">book</a>. Will postpone this for a minute while I read it, but it doesn’t seem very promising.</p> <p>The author changed his name to be the same as my dad, which is freaky, the <a href="https://silvamethod.com/store/silva-life-system-the-core-of-silva-method-program/">steps</a> and a twitter search seem to mean is another cult pretending to be more effective than it is. They obviously charge money for courses and have certified instructors and other red flags. I’m sure is helpful to some folks and good for them.</p> <p>Anyway, I’m not interested in joining or starting an institute of the sort, or being affiliated with them.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[wellbeing is not something you can buy]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GloriaJS - simple framework for static websites</title><link href="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2022/gloria-js/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GloriaJS - simple framework for static websites"/><published>2022-12-28T00:04:20+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-28T00:04:20+00:00</updated><id>https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2022/gloria-js</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dvidsilva.com/posts/2022/gloria-js/"><![CDATA[<p>I got very frustrated with ruby one day and decided to make my own static website generator, like how hard can it be? read the indicatedd folders for files, decide which layout to use to wrap the content, output in another folder and deploy to github pages.</p> <p>Gloriav1 worked out of the box 6+ years later after the first commit, tho node has changed a lot and my old code wasn’t great. I hadn’t figure out a few things back then and decided to take some shortcuts to keep releasing. Even had somme folks send pull requests and add features, pretty neat.</p> <p>So here we are again, v2 released yesterday or something, and it doesn’t output websites yet, but it works really well, and soon this website would migrate to it, probably using the migration tool I’ll be writing over the weekend or some time in the future. This time around will focus on tailwind only, is very fast to learn and use, the compile is much smarter this time, so it would be easy for anyone to create developers for other tools compatible with postcss or whatever i end frankisteining.</p> <p>This time around every step is independent, so that they can be more decoupled and evolve on their own direction. The actual command execution, and the event listeners for <a href="http://yargs.js.org/">yargs</a> are in separate files now also.</p> <p>The program does something like:</p> <ul> <li><strong>collect</strong></li> <li><strong>extract</strong></li> <li><strong>prebuild</strong></li> <li><strong>build</strong></li> <li><strong>output</strong></li> <li><strong>deploy</strong></li> </ul> <p>Every step is pretty self explanatory I guess, or read the source code, hoping to keep every step customizable by allowing to monkey patch operations and the ability to add plugins. In order for it to keep working tho, the API must be backwards compatible and all that, that’s why this time around the installation is local to the project, easier to ignore the whims of the developer if you can lock to a version.</p> <p>We’ll see what happens, kisses.</p> <p><a href="https://gloria.js.org/">website</a></p> <p><a href="https://github.com/gloriajs/gloria">github</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[create simple static websites, open source & free hosting]]></summary></entry></feed>